ryorevolution.com 2011-03-15

# Privacy Policy | RYO Revolution

**Scope**

 _The Collection and Use of Information_

RYO Revolution collects information from you under the following two circumstances: 

  * Information Collected Automatically - Some information is collected from you automatically when you view RYO Revolution pages and download information. This may include your Internet Protocol address assigned by your Internet Service Provider, domain name and the type of browser and operating system you used, the date and time you accessed RYO Revolution's site, the pages you requested and visited, and the site you linked from to reach RYO Revolution. RYO Revolution uses this type of information to statistically measure site traffic and to improve the web site. The information is not reviewed on an individual basis but is aggregated with other users for comparison purposes.
  * Information Voluntarily Submitted - Additional information may be collected from you if you opt-in or voluntarily provide it in order to: 
    1. fulfill a request for on-line services or
    2. choose to personalize the site (register for a RYO Revolution forum account).

RYO Revolution uses the information you voluntarily provide to tailor our site to your needs and preferences and to provide the on-line services you are requesting. The type of information we collect will vary with the service being sought. To register a forum account requires that you provide a user name, valid e-mail address and verification that you are at least 18 years old. If you simply wish to view pages on RYO Revolution's site or forums you Do Not need to personalize the site by registering for an account. 

_Cookies_

In order to customize your browsing experience, RYO Revolution uses "cookies". Cookies allow information to change as you navigate through the pages of a web site. Two types of cookies can be used, "session-only" and "persistent". RYO Revolution uses cookies in the following ways: 

  1. If you wish to access the site or forums but do not want to personalize the forums, RYO Revolution uses session-only cookies to reserve some storage on your computer in order to take your query and pass it along to the page that will serve up the information you request. The session-only cookies are erased either during web browser operation or after your web browser is shut down.
  2. If you choose to register with RYO Revolution to personalize the forum to your preferences but do not wish to be remembered, RYO Revolution uses session cookies that are destroyed when you close your browser.
  3. If you choose to register with RYO Revolution to personalize the forums and wish to be remembered, RYO Revolution uses permanent cookies that remain on your computer's hard drive as small text files. These permanent cookies allow RYO Revolution to recognize you when you return to our site. When you register with RYO Revolution, we ask you to identify yourself by your user name and email address. This allows RYO Revolution to customize the presentation of information for you based upon what you have asked for and/or voluntarily provided during previous visits. RYO Revolution only uses permanent cookies with the permission of the user.
  4. RYO Revolution also uses 3rd party advertisers to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information cookies to track your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you wish to opt out of the DART cookie used by the Google adsense program or read more about Google's advertising and privacy policies, you can do so [here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "Google advertising and privacy policy").

RYO Revolution has links to other web sites outside of our site. When you link to one of these sites, RYO Revolution cannot control their use of cookies and this privacy policy will not apply. 

If you choose to do so, you can configure your browser to notify you when a new cookie is received. You can also prevent your browser from accepting any new cookies, view and delete existing cookies or disable cookies altogether.

 _Information Sharing and Disclosure_

RYO Revolution will only send personal information about you to others when: 

  * we have your consent to share the information; or
  * we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have specifically requested; or
  * we are compelled to do so by law (e.g., to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, or to requests pursuant to a statute requiring disclosure).

_Editing and Deleting Your Account Information_

You will be able to edit your RYO Revolution forum account information and preferences at any time by accessing your User Control Panel within the forums. If you wish to have your RYO Revolution forum account deleted you must send a request for account deletion to the forum administrator either from your forum account or from your registered email address to forums (AT) ryoreovlution.com 

_Changes to this Privacy Policy_

RYO Revolution may amend this policy from time to time. RYO Revolution will prominently display on this website any substantial change in the way we use your personal information.
